

# CONTACT

+234 70 664 012 70

benzimakareem26@gmail.com

Lagos, Nigeria. Willing to Relocate

#### PROFILE

Portfolio: kokoblackdev.vercel.app

Github: @kokoblack

LinkedIn: @kokoblack

# LANGUAGES

- HTML5
- CSS3/SCSS
- JavaScript (ES6+)
- TypeScript

# JS FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

- React.js, Next.js, Redux
- Vue.js, Vuex, Pinia, Nuxt
- Angular.js
- GraphQL
- Axios (Rest APIs)

# UI FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

- Tailwind
- Chakra UI
- Ant-Design
- Styled-Components

# HARUNA ABDUL KAREEM

## FRONTEND ENGINEER

Quality oriented professional with more than 3 years of experience and proven knowledge in website design and front-end engineering frameworks and technologies. Strong creative and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the front-end engineering role at your company.

# EXPERIENCE

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER

Jun 2022 - Now

Groupify

As a frontend Engineer at Groupify, I am primarily responsible for handling the frontend development of the Groupify Web App and Web site. At Groupify I:

- Was solely responsible for developing the customer facing website which helped in establishing an online presence
- Integrated APIs for core user activities like member registration, KYC and payout/withdrawal
- Optimized API calls by defining Fragments, composing Graphs and grouping multiple Querys into a single Query
- Refactored numerous modules of the WebApp by utilizing best practices, state, low coupling and high cohesion design patterns
- Developed the public sales page, member registration and other core user interface pages on the Web App by creating component variants

Skills:- ReactJs | TypeScript | GraphQl | Tailwind | SCSS | AnimeJs | Git | CI/CD

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Flutterwave

- A Collaborated with other engineers and stakeholders in building the Rave V3 Web Application, improving load time, accessibility and user experience
- A Implemented core functionalities like customer onboarding, profile and business settings, customer dashboard and more, using Nuxt
- A Handled state management using the Vuex library

Skills:- NuxtJS| VueX| Chakra UI| SCSS | SEO| Git | Axios

# TESTING FRAMEWORKS

- Jest
- Cypress

#### VERSION CONTROL

- Git
- Github
- Gitlab

#### PROJECT MANAGER

- Trello
- Linear
- Slack

#### LEARNING & INT

- WebGL
- Web3

#### CONCEPTS

- Object oriented programming
- Responsive design
- Mobile first design
- E2E testing
- Agile methodology
- Atomic design pattern
- React design pattern

#### OTHERS

Sanity.io, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, Figma

# EDUCATION

B.S.C.(E.D), COMPUTER SCIENCE EDUCATION

2017 - 2022

# LANGUAGE

**English** 

#### **O** FRONTEND ENGINEER

TangerineAfrica

As a Frontend Engineer at Tangerine Africa, I develop digital products in the Financial and Insurance sector. My work involves building in accordance to specifications provided by both the design and product team. At Tangerine Africa, I've:

- Participated and contributed in brainstorming sessions for application features
- Facilitated the integration of Mailgun and Netlify, created email template and wrote server less functions to send auto response emails and store submissions for lead generation
- Integrated third party APIs for BVN and selfie matching, this helped to improve customer Identity
- Implemented feature flags for removal of the specific features for targeted customers on The Tangerine Africa Platform
- Implemented UI designs and integrated APIs for the dashboard and website re-design, providing more accessibility for users
- Fixed unnecessary page reload for core components with global state management. This improved the performance and UX of the web application
- Acted as the primary frontend engineer for the migration of existing users from the various Sub-Cos(Pension, Money, Insurance) onto The Tangerine Africa Platform
- Participated in Sprint Demos, while making sure that all feedbacks from stake-holders are captured and resolved

Skills:- AngularJs | NuxtJs | TypeScript | Axios | SCSS | Git | CI/CD

## FRONTEND ENGINEER (CONTRACT)

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

Mar 2021 - Now

Rizevo

- Standardized all output with responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy
- A Architected the entire client-end for the Customer, Business and Admin modules of the Web-app
- A Completed, deployed and set up CI/CD for all web modules using netlify and github.

Skills:- ReactJs | Redux | Ant-Design | Axios | Netlify | Git

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER

Mar 2020 - Feb 2022

Flex Me

- Developed a custom, modular component library, which served as building blocks for the Web application
- Developed the customer facing website which helped in establishing an online presence and aided advertisement
- Designed and developed the customer facing Website using Figma and NuxtJs
- Implemented best practices and optimization techniques with significantly reduced project's build time

Skills:- VueJs | Vuex | ReactJs | Redux | SCSS | SEO | Axios | Git